Pablo Gastelum

Front-end Developer

Detail-oriented frontend developer with a product design background. Knowledgeable in user interfaces, wireframing and react application development.

Experienced in developing re-usable components and application debugging. Able to collaborate in a team setting and implement performance efficient solutions in the least amount of time.

Sonora, Mexico +52 81 1909 9454

pablo.g.leyva@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/pablogastelum github.com/pgast

education

Bachelor in Product Design

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León

Aug 2011 - Dec 2016 Monterrey, Mexico

skills

HTML5 Node.js
CSS Express.js
Javascript (ES6) jQuery
React.js Bootstrap
Redux Git

Communication Graphic design
Problem solving UX / UI design
Active learning Adobe (AI, PS)
Collaboration 3D Modeling

awards / recognition

Finalist / Green refrigeration unit 2015 IMBERA Refrigeration

First Prize / Toy design proposal 2014 Kinder Surprise Me!

International Competition

languages

Spanish - Native
English - Fluent
French - Conversational

Portuguese - Conversational

projects

Woodcalc

Web app that calculates how much wood is required for a project. Takes into account wood types, waste ratios and invidual parts and dimensions.

/pgast/wood-calc

Bitechoice

Web app that fetches places to eat near you or around the world. Built using the YELP API with an Express.js server to bypass CORS.

/pgast/bite-choice

Dashtabs

QR based order management for food businesses. Connected to a back-end database; it allows owners to see orders in real time, display and update menus.

/pgast/dash-tabs

Split

Progressive web app that helps breakdown expenses between people. Useful for events, reunions and projects.

/pgast/split

work experience

Designer / Macizo Carpintería

Hermosillo, Mexico

ducing pre-manufac-

Apr 2018 - Current

- Developed web app that calculates wood wastage reducing pre-manufacturing time nearly 10%.
- Formulated new user friendly guidelines for production blueprints reducing construction errors by 20%.
- Delivered design and engineering woodwork concepts for worldwide hotel chains and residential clients.

Product Designer / G3 Fabricación

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

Monterrey, Mexico

- Conceptualization of commercial interior design concepts.
- Worked with construction team to achieve project deadlines.
- Generated 3D visualizations of concepts and product engineering.

Design Intern / Jorge Diego Etienne Design Studio Mar 2016 - Aug 2016 Monterrey, Mexico

- Collaborated in user research planning, execution and analysis.
- Generated computer models and visualizations.
- Built physical models and mockups for idea validation.

Junior Designer / Marley Industrial Supply

Jun 2011 - Feb 2013

Monterrey, Mexico

- Conceptualized a set of safety signage for industrial equipment, reducing costs and dependance on outside providers.
- Produced blueprints and 3D visualizations improving project installation time by workers.

training / courses

Over 700 hours of online learning.

The Web Developer Bootcamp Udemy Certificate

43 hours

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structure Masterclass

Udemy Certificate

22 hours

Front-End

FreeCodeCamp Certificate

400 hours

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures

FreeCodeCamp Certificate

300 hours